<idea-plugin>
    <id>fr.fsh.tokendesigner</id>
    <name>Token Flow</name>
    <vendor email="robinlopez.contact@gmail.com">Robin Lopez</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
<!-- Marketplace banner -->
<p>Make using your tokens intuitive.<br/>
Token Flow helps you find the right variable and keep your styles flawless without ever leaving your IntelliJ code.</p>

<p><b>Token Flow</b> indexes your whole Design System and makes token usage fluid, fast and error-proof.<br/>
Supported formats: SCSS variables, CSS Custom Properties, SCSS Maps, TS/JS preset objects, React Native runtime themes and helpers.</p>

<h3>Superpowers for Front-end Developers</h3>

<ul>
  <li><b>Instant Search (Library)</b><br/>
      A dedicated side panel to find tokens by name, value or category.<br/>
      Includes visual swatches and drag-and-drop support.</li>
  <li><b>Smart Swapping <code>(Alt+T)</code></b><br/>
      Need a slightly darker blue or the next spacing scale?<br/>
      Token Flow suggests siblings based on HSL proximity, logical order, or scale steps for callable helpers like <code>spacing()</code>.</li>
  <li><b>Zero "Magic Numbers"</b><br/>
      The IDE flags hardcoded hex codes, pixels or unitless numbers that match an existing token — one click and your code is clean.</li>
  <li><b>Inline Suggestions</b><br/>
      As you type a value, matching tokens appear without stealing focus.</li>
  <li><b>Deep Context</b><br/>
      Hover any token to see its resolved value, aliases and per-mode variants
      (Dark / Light / breakpoints).</li>
  <li><b>Full-scale Audit</b><br/>
      An "Analyse" tab grades your project health.<br/>
      Identify tech debt, unused tokens and hardcoded clusters in seconds.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Real-world Use Cases</h3>

<ul>
  <li><b>Rapid Integration</b> — code a UI component without leaving the current
      file to check the token naming convention.</li>
  <li><b>Theme Debugging</b> — see instantly how a token resolves in Dark vs
      Light mode via the hover popup.</li>
  <li><b>System Migration</b> — refactor legacy CSS/SCSS by detecting every
      hardcoded value that should have been a token.</li>
  <li><b>Consistency Check</b> — keep multi-brand projects aligned with
      <i>Scopes</i> to isolate tokens per platform or sub-project.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Made by</h3>

<p><b>Robin Lopez</b> — designer & front-end engineer.<br/>
<a href="https://www.robinlopez.fr/">robinlopez.fr</a> ·
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/robin-lopez-designer/">LinkedIn</a> ·
<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lopezrobin.bsky.social">Bluesky</a> ·
<a href="https://robinlopez.github.io/robinlopezbento/">Bento</a></p>

<p>
  <a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/robinlopez">
    <img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/doiw6rqul/image/upload/v1778160520/Token%20Flow/buy-coffee-btn.png" alt="Buy Me A Coffee" width="250" height="54"/>
  </a>
</p>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
<h3>0.1.9 — Smarter broken-reference detection</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>CSS variables declared outside token sources are no longer flagged as broken</b>: Token Flow now picks up two new families of declaration. <i>Runtime injection</i> from component code — Angular <code>[style.--var]</code> host bindings, React/Vue inline-style object keys, <code>setProperty('--var', …)</code> calls. <i>Contextual CSS overrides</i> — any <code>--name: value</code> declaration in any <code>.css</code>/<code>.scss</code>/<code>.sass</code>/<code>.vue</code> rule body, so the <i>CSS Custom Property API</i> pattern (generic component reads <code>var(--c, fallback)</code>, consumers set <code>--c</code> locally) just works.</li>
  <li><b>Fallbacks no longer hide missing variables</b>: <code>var(--x, inherit)</code> is still flagged when <code>--x</code> is nowhere to be found — a runtime default is not a license to leave a dangling reference.</li>
  <li><b>New setting</b>: Settings → Token Flow → Analyser → "Recognise CSS variables declared outside token sources". On by default; uncheck to revert to the strict pre-0.1.9 behaviour.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.8 — Sharper token suggestions (tier &amp; role aware)</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>External token prefixes (per scope)</b>: new <i>External</i> tab in Settings → Token Flow → Scopes for CSS-var prefixes injected at runtime by an external framework : PrimeNG <code>--p-</code>, Ionic <code>--ion-</code>, Angular Material <code>--mat-</code>, Material Web <code>--mdc-</code>, Vuetify <code>--v-</code>, Bootstrap <code>--bs-</code>, Radix <code>--radix-</code>, Quasar <code>--q-</code>, Element Plus <code>--el-</code>, Mantine, Carbon, … References matching a configured prefix are never flagged as broken by the Analyser or the Hardcoded Values panel.</li>
  <li><b>Auto-detect from <code>package.json</code></b>: one-click button in the External tab that scans the project for known framework dependencies and adds their prefixes to the scope.</li>
  <li><b>Project-open detection notification</b>: opening a project that depends on a known UI framework but has no prefixes configured surfaces a balloon offering <i>Add to all scopes</i> / <i>Configure…</i> / <i>Don't show again</i>. One-shot — never nags twice.</li>
  <li><b>JSON config v2</b>: exports/imports now carry <code>externalPrefixes</code> per scope. v1 files remain importable.</li>
  <li><b>Hardcoded Values : token-source files are skipped</b>: opening a file declared in any scope's <code>sourcePaths</code> now shows an explanatory banner and disables the scan. No more flagging of <code>--units-xl: 32px;</code> as hardcoded when the file's purpose is to declare it.</li>
  <li><b>Hardcoded Values : SCSS map values are no longer flagged</b>: literals inside a <code>$name: (…)</code> or <code>"key": (…)</code> SCSS map (Style-Dictionary / theme-config pattern) are recognised as token definitions and skipped. Handles nested maps to any depth, even when the file isn't formally declared as a token source — useful for mixed files.</li>
  <li><b>Hardcoded Values : search &amp; property filter</b>: new search field filters rows by literal, selector, surrounding CSS property, or suggested token (multi-term, case-insensitive). A filter button opens a popup with every detected CSS property grouped by category (Spacing, Color, Radius…), with counts, and a nested search to narrow the property checklist. The previous toolbar toggle <i>"Hide rows without a token suggestion"</i> moves into this popup.</li>
  <li><b>Token tier awareness</b>: when several DS tokens share the same value (<code>--units-xl</code> and <code>--spacing-xl</code> both <code>32px</code>), the suggestion engine now prefers the <i>semantic</i> token over the <i>primitive</i> one. Primitive prefixes recognised: <code>units-</code>, <code>palette-</code>, <code>base-</code>, <code>primitive-</code>, <code>core-</code>, <code>scale-</code>, <code>raw-</code>. So <code>padding: 32px</code> now suggests <code>var(--spacing-xl)</code> instead of <code>var(--units-xl)</code>.</li>
  <li><b>Property-to-role matching for colors</b>: <code>background</code>, <code>color</code>, <code>border-color</code>, <code>box-shadow</code>… now derive an expected <i>role</i> (surface / content / stroke / effect) and match it against token-name segments. Tokens carrying the right role get a strong boost; tokens carrying a conflicting role are demoted. So <code>background: #005bff</code> prefers <code>token-actions-high-surface-default</code> over <code>global-default-content-default</code>, and <code>color: #001a70</code> does the opposite.</li>
  <li><b>Multi-criterion ranking</b>: the suggestion score was rewritten as a weighted combination of (category, role, tier, exact-vs-fuzzy, length). Token-name length is now only a tiebreaker — a longer-but-more-semantic name can outrank a shorter primitive one, which was impossible before.</li>
  <li><b>Fuzzy color tiebreaking</b>: when no exact color match exists, ties at near-identical RGB distance are broken by the semantic score so the role-appropriate token surfaces first.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.7 — Portable scope configuration, smarter Library &amp; Vue SFCs</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Vue Single File Components (<code>.vue</code>)</b>: tokens declared in <code>&lt;style&gt;</code> and <code>&lt;style lang="scss"&gt;</code> blocks of a Vue SFC are now indexed, listed in the Library, counted in audit coverage, and benefit from hardcoded-value detection / completion / Alt+T / Go-to-declaration. Text-based implementation — no dependency on the Vue plugin — so it works on Community and Ultimate. Scanning is confined to inline style blocks, so <code>&lt;template&gt;</code> and <code>&lt;script&gt;</code> sections stay untouched.</li>
  <li><b>Export Config</b>: Settings → Token Flow → Scopes now has an <i>Export…</i> link that writes the current scopes to a JSON file. Share it with the team, commit it next to the project, or keep it as a backup.</li>
  <li><b>Import Config</b>: paired <i>Import…</i> link reads a JSON file produced by Export. The plugin asks whether to <b>Replace</b> the current scopes or <b>Merge</b> (existing scopes with the same name are overwritten, new ones are appended). Pending edits are persisted via Apply, so a teammate can preview the import before committing.</li>
  <li><b>Versioned format</b>: the JSON file carries a schema version. Older Token Flow builds refuse files produced by a future schema instead of silently dropping fields.</li>
  <li><b>Library family / sub-family grouping</b>: inside each big category accordion, the Library can now insert a two-level hierarchy of headers — family (<code>HIGH</code>, <code>LOW</code>, <code>PRIMARY</code>) and sub-family (<code>SURFACE</code>, <code>CONTENT</code>, <code>STROKE</code>, …) — derived from the structure of token names alone. No hard-coded vocabulary; the algorithm adapts to any naming convention. Tokens indent under their header so the alignment reads like a tree. New toolbar toggle (group-by icon) next to the view-mode button; off by default — opt in from the panel.</li>
  <li><b>Sticky category header</b>: scroll past a category and its header pins to the top of the Library viewport, with the same chevron behaviour as the in-list row.</li>
  <li><b>Justified category bar</b>: layout is now <code>[chevron] TITLE … (count)</code>, with the count badge tinted so it can't be mistaken for a resolved token value.</li>
  <li><b>Two-way kind / file-chip sync</b>: ticking a token-kind in the Library filter popup now flips every file chip of that kind in the strip below the search bar, and vice-versa — the two filter surfaces no longer drift.</li>
  <li><b>Variant tooltip — vertical layout</b>: per-variant tooltips now render one line per variant (label left, swatch / glyph + value right) instead of a wide horizontal table that overflowed once a token had several variants. Multi-theme tokens get discrete theme subheaders.</li>
  <li><b>Hardcoded Values — tighter rows &amp; hide-no-match filter</b>: rows nest under their selector header, the literal column is narrower, the suggestion combo is taller (no more clipped descenders), and a new toolbar toggle hides literals without any matching token (on by default — broken references stay visible because they're actionable).</li>
  <li><b>Light-theme polish</b>: Library category / family / sub-family palette rebuilt with proper light-vs-dark contrast steps (the previous sub-family pair was inverted), and the dark bands that appeared behind separator headers on light themes are gone — <code>gridContainer</code>, the sticky header and the grid viewport now follow <code>list.background</code>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.6 — Smarter Library, sharper Analyser</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Multi-term Library search</b>: <code>"informative content"</code> now finds <code>--token-informative-highlight-content-hover</code>. Search splits on spaces/dashes/underscores, every term must match.</li>
  <li><b>Library kind filter</b>: the funnel popup gets a <i>Token kind</i> section (CSS / SCSS / JS-JSON) above <i>Families</i>. The button highlights when any filter is active.</li>
  <li><b>Context-aware JS token drop</b>: drag or paste a <code>'{path}'</code> token inside a backtick template literal in TS/JS and it lands as <code>${dt('path')}</code> (or <code>dt('path')</code> inside an existing <code>${…}</code>).</li>
  <li><b>Stale-analysis banner</b>: after a run, the Analyser watches every file referenced by the report; editing one surfaces a yellow banner offering one-click re-run.</li>
  <li><b>Reorderable scopes</b>: up/down arrows in Settings, order reflected immediately in the Analyser scope picker.</li>
  <li><b>Excluded from Analysis (per scope)</b>: new <i>Excludes</i> tab to carve unrelated sub-modules out of a wide scope root.</li>
  <li><b>Tabbed scope detail</b>: Sources / Whitelist / Excludes split into tabs — no more vertical scroll in the Settings dialog.</li>
  <li><b>Cleaner Analyser toolbar</b>: redundant <i>Refresh</i> / <i>Re-sync scopes</i> removed; the single action flips to <i>Re-run analysis</i> once a report exists.</li>
  <li><b>Alt+T preserves <code>dt(…)</code></b>: picking an alternative on <code>${dt('token.x.y')}</code> no longer rewrites it into a bare Style-Dictionary alias and breaks the surrounding template literal.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.5 — Broken-reference detection &amp; sharper suggestions</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Broken Reference Detection</b>: the Analyser lists token references that don't resolve (<code>var(--foo)</code>, <code>'{token.x.y}'</code>, <code>dt('x.y')</code>) in a dedicated section, and the Hardcoded Values panel flags them inline with a yellow warning. A new <i>Reference integrity</i> axis (20 % weight) joins the global score.</li>
  <li><b>Resilient JS/TS reference matching</b>: alt+T, completion and go-to now resolve Style-Dictionary refs like <code>'{token.modeLight.informative.default.high.surface.default}'</code> against canonical tokens — leading export binding (<code>token.</code>), mode segment (<code>modeLight</code> / <code>modeDark</code>) and a single camelCase merge / split per path (<code>default.high</code> ↔ <code>defaultHigh</code>) are all tolerated.</li>
  <li><b>CSS <code>var()</code> inside TS template literals</b>: alt+T now recognises <code>var(--name)</code> inside backtick strings in <code>.ts/.tsx</code>; CSS functional notations (<code>var</code>, <code>calc</code>, <code>rgb*</code>, <code>hsl*</code>, gradients, transforms) are no longer mistaken for JS helper calls.</li>
  <li><b>Category-scoped suggestions</b>: <code>padding: 6px</code> no longer suggests a 6 px shadow-blur token. The value index is keyed by <code>(category, value)</code> with controlled fallback inside the length family (SPACING, RADIUS, SIZING, TYPOGRAPHY, BORDER).</li>
  <li><b>Smarter incoherence judgement</b>: <code>--stroke-default: 1px</code> is no longer flagged when the categorizer has already reconciled the name/value clash (here: BORDER).</li>
  <li><b>Ignored library files</b>: new Settings list to exclude vendored design-system packages from the analyser.</li>
  <li><b>Scanner refinements</b>: values inside comments and inside <code>var(--x, fallback)</code> fallbacks are no longer reported. Standard CSS named colors are detected. Circular token definitions are no longer flagged as hardcoded.</li>
  <li><b>UI polish</b>: scope display in the Hardcoded Values panel, scope info right-aligned in toolbars, expandable long Analyser sections, fixed accordion-gap inflation, "Non-existent tokens" renamed to "Broken references".</li>
  <li><b>API hygiene</b>: removed all usages of IntelliJ APIs marked deprecated or scheduled-for-removal so the plugin loads cleanly on the latest IDE builds.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.4 — Visual Grid &amp; Polished UX</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Design System Dashboard - Grid View</b>: New visual mode representing tokens as beautiful, interactive cards. Includes visual previews for colors, spacing, and radius.</li>
  <li><b>Smarter Categorization</b>: Added 6 new categories (EFFECTS, LAYOUT, BORDER, etc.) and refined the engine to flawlessly classify complex semantic tokens.</li>
  <li><b>Contextual Scope Awareness</b>: The Dashboard and Analyser now dynamically track and display your currently edited file's scope.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.3 — Gutter swatches &amp; SCSS modifiers</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Gutter color swatches for SCSS</b>: variables (<code>$name</code>) now display a color preview icon in the gutter, resolving through the project index (consistent with native CSS variables).</li>
  <li><b>Robust SCSS/CSS parsing</b>: modifiers like <code>!default</code>, <code>!global</code>, and <code>!important</code> are now stripped during extraction, fixing color previews and alias resolution for flagged tokens.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.2 — React Native support</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>React Native runtime themes</b>: property-access tokens
      (<code>colors.PRIMARY_500</code>, <code>theme.radius.sm</code>,
      <code>fontPresets.h1.fontSize</code>) are now detected.
      Typed <code>export const X: Type = {…}</code> aggregators contribute
      leaf paths only (aligned with barrel re-exports); bare <code>const X = {…}</code> bags keep their prefix.
      Cross-object alias resolution included.</li>
  <li><b>Callable helpers (<code>spacing</code>, <code>radius</code>, …)</b>:
      linear arrow functions like <code>(v) =&gt; UNIT * v</code> are indexed
      with a ƒ badge. Hardcoded <code>12</code> now suggests
      <code>spacing(1.5)</code>. <code>Alt+T</code> on <code>spacing(0.5)</code>
      opens a scale popup (<code>spacing(0.25)</code>, <code>spacing(0.5)</code>,
      <code>spacing(1)</code>, <code>spacing(1.5)</code>, …).</li>
  <li><b>Unitless numerics flagged</b>: <code>fontSize: 34</code>,
      <code>lineHeight: 24</code>, <code>opacity: 0.5</code> now inspected
      against the token index (JS/TS only). Numbers inside a helper call are
      ignored to avoid noise.</li>
  <li><b>Suggest matching tokens as you type</b>: the value-completion popup
      no longer steals editor focus — typing keeps going into the file.</li>
  <li><b>Analyser respects the selected scope</b>: file walk is restricted to
      the scope's <code>rootPath</code>; only the active scope's own catalogues
      are excluded. Scope changes in Settings refresh the picker live; a
      <b>Re-sync</b> action is available for manual cache drops.</li>
  <li><b>Architecture</b>: TS/JS parsing reorganised into a strategy package
      (<code>StyleDictionaryParser</code>, <code>RuntimeObjectParser</code>,
      <code>RuntimeFunctionParser</code>, registry to dispatch per file).
      Adding a new stack now means plugging in a single class.</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.1 — Polish &amp; bug fixes</h3>
<ul>
  <li><b>Hover popup — multi-theme grouping</b>: tokens declared under nested
      SCSS maps (<code>$themes-config -&gt; "themeOne" -&gt; "light" -&gt; …</code>)
      now render with theme-grouped column headers instead of a flat
      <code>default | dark | light | dark</code> sequence.</li>
  <li><b>Settings — Scopes tab</b>: long intro hints no longer trigger a
      horizontal scrollbar when the dialog is narrow; HTML paragraphs wrap
      properly inside the available width.</li>
  <li>Marketplace metadata cleanup (vendor contact, simplified description).</li>
</ul>

<h3>0.1.0 — First public release</h3>
<p>The first iteration of Token Flow ships everything you need to manage your Design System directly inside the IDE.</p>
<ul>
  <li><b>Multi-format indexer</b> — SCSS, CSS, and TS/JS support with alias resolution.</li>
  <li><b>Library Tool Window</b> — Visual search, drag-and-drop, and navigation.</li>
  <li><b>Alternatives Popup (Alt+T)</b> — Smart sorting for colors and metrics.</li>
  <li><b>Hardcoded Inspection</b> — Automatic detection and quick-fix for literals.</li>
  <li><b>Analyse Tab</b> — Deep health report and technical debt tracking.</li>
  <li><b>Scopes</b> — Multi-UI project support.</li>
</ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <notificationGroup id="DesignTokenSelector"
                           displayType="BALLOON"
                           bundle="messages.TokenBundle"
                           key="notification.group.name"/>

        <projectConfigurable parentId="tools"
                             id="DesignTokenSelector.Settings"
                             displayName="Token Flow"
                             instance="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.settings.TokenSelectorConfigurable"/>

        <toolWindow id="Design Tokens"
                    anchor="right"
                    icon="/icons/icon-tokenflow-default.png"
                    factoryClass="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.ui.DesignTokenToolWindowFactory"/>

        <postStartupActivity implementation="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.hover.HoverPopupStartup"/>

        <completion.contributor language="any"
                                implementationClass="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.completion.TokenCompletionContributor"/>

        <localInspection language="any"
                         shortName="DesignTokenHardcodedValue"
                         displayName="Hardcoded value matches a design token"
                         groupName="Token Flow"
                         enabledByDefault="true"
                         level="WEAK WARNING"
                         implementationClass="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.inspection.HardcodedValueInspection"/>

        <typedHandler implementation="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.completion.ValueCompletionTypedHandler"/>

        <postStartupActivity implementation="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.completion.ValueCompletionStartup"/>

        <postStartupActivity implementation="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.settings.FrameworkPrefixNotifier"/>

        <colorProvider implementation="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.provider.TokenColorProvider"/>

        <copyPastePostProcessor implementation="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.actions.JsTokenPathPasteProcessor"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="DesignTokenSelector.ShowAllTokens"
                class="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.actions.ShowAllTokensAction"
                text="Show All Design Tokens"
                description="Scans the project and lists every detected design token">
            <add-to-group group-id="ToolsMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>

        <action id="DesignTokenSelector.ShowAlternatives"
                class="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.actions.ShowTokenAlternativesAction"
                text="Show Token Alternatives"
                description="Shows alternatives of the design token under the caret">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="alt T"/>
        </action>

        <action id="DesignTokenSelector.GoToDeclaration"
                class="fr.fsh.tokendesigner.actions.GoToTokenDeclarationAction"
                text="Go to Token Declaration"
                description="Opens the file where the token under the caret is declared">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <keyboard-shortcut keymap="$default" first-keystroke="alt shift T"/>
            <mouse-shortcut keymap="$default" keystroke="alt shift button1"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
